ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
小酸奶!
翻译
时间轴
念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第八集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
电器
酸豆
好心二手店
捐赠中心
她睡下了吗
Is she down?
嗯
Yeah.
结束了吧  请告诉我都结束了
Is it over? Please tell me it's over.
我爱我父母  但是老天啊
I love my parents, but, good God...
他们走了
They're gone.
一小时后  他们将登上
In an hour, they will be in the air
回德州的飞机
on their way back to Texas.
他们走了
They are gone.
他们现在归环球航空公司操心了
They are TWA's problem now.
但是  不  不
But, no. No!
为什么
Why?!
保证我们以后绝对不会像他们那样看待彼此
Promise me we will never look at each other the way they do.
我保证不了
I can't promise.
对不起他们让你那么抓狂
Sorry they drive you so crazy.
你在说什么  他们人那么好
What are you talking about? They were great.
你看你爸爸给了我什么
You see what your dad got me?
能时刻提醒我
The perfect reminder
他觉得我有多娘
of how unmanly he thinks I am.
声音真尖
Screechy.
我们为什么还要改进
Yeah, why we need to improve upon a tool
一件已很好地服务了人类
that's been serving mankind brilliantly
几百万年的工具  我真不懂
for millions of years is beyond me.
我去
Damn.
这玩意真锋利
This baby's really sharp.
给我拿个旧靴子
Hey, give me an old boot.
看看这东西有多大能耐
Let's see what this thing can do.
别闹了  你会把她吵醒的
Stop it. ‭You're gonna wake her up.
好吧
Oh, fine.
每次我妈妈手里拿着夏敦埃时
I'm always amazed at what my mom can do
都能做出很多让我意想不到的事
with a glass of Chardonnay in her hand.
她都能加入马戏团了
She could join the circus.
你觉得他们玩得开心吗
Hey, you think they had fun?
开心
Yeah.
我不确定我妈妈喜不喜欢这幢楼
I'm not sure my mom approved of the building,
还有周围环境什么的  但是
or the neighborhood for that matter, but...
她就只在乎体面
you know, it's all about appearances to her.
你听到你爸爸怎么说
Yeah. And did you hear what your dad said
那些种花生的农民
about the peanut farmer
和关于节能的抨击吗
and his whole ‭energy-conservation diatribe?
不  没有  我听不下去
No, don't. I can't.
还说我们应该住在
Or the line about how we should live in an area
房东比租客多的地方
with more homeowners than renters.
你知道那是什么意思吧
You know what that's code for.
至少他们跟琼妮处得挺好
Well...at least they're good with Joanie.
你妈妈跟她处得非常好
Your mom is great with her.
我爸爸也是
Well, so is my dad.
他的确不打孩子  如果你是这个意思的话
I mean, he didn't strike the child, if that's what you mean.
他还不会在她脑袋边上放烟花
Yeah, he also managed not to set off any fireworks next to her head.
就那么一个火箭瓶
It was one bottle rocket.
天啊  你有没有看到琼妮吐在他那件
Oh, my God. ‭Did you see the look on his face
有特殊意义的独立日短袖衫上时他的表情
when Joanie spit up ‭on his special 4th of July Polo?
她算是帮了那件短袖衫个忙
She was doing that shirt a favor.
他想帮忙  只是不知道该怎么做
He tries to help. He just doesn't always know how.
提出要给我们买一幢在达拉斯的房子
Offering to buy us a house as long as it's in Dallas.
别这样  接受一点他们的帮助
Come on. I mean, would it be the worst thing in the world
也没有那么糟糕吧
if we had a little bit of help?
我们不需要帮助
We don't need help.
为什么  你想永远住在这里吗
Why? Do you want to live here forever?
唐娜  我们不会永远住在这里的
Look, Donna, we are not gonna live here forever, okay?
我们会造出东西  造出一台机器
Okay, we're gonna build something, a machine, okay?
我们要一起卖出个好价钱
And we're gonna sell it together.
是吗  那得等到猴年马月
Oh, yeah? And when are we gonna do that?
照顾孩子  换尿布
Between nursing and changing diapers
而且只有我才能哄她睡觉
and being the only one that can get the baby to sleep,
我觉得我未来没多少时间
I don't really see a whole lot of time for
去造电脑
building computers in my future.
不会一直那样的
Yeah, well, it's not always gonna be like that.
-是吗  -是啊
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
什么会变呢
What's gonna change?
我不知道  所有东西吧
I don't know. I mean, everything.
希望吧  因为我可不想下半辈子
Well, I hope so, 'cause I don't want to be breastfeeding
都在哺乳和洗碗中度过
and doing dishes the rest of my life.
这才三个月
Look, it's been three months.
在德州  我这时都能去上班了
Well, in Texas, ‭I'd be freed up to go to work,
你也是
and so would you.
我们不是真要讨论搬回德州的事吧
We're not actually talking about moving back to Texas right now.
我妈妈说如果我们想...
My mom said that if we wanted --
你和你妈妈谈过这件事吗
You've been talking to your mom about this?
你们有什么计划吗
Well -- What, are you guys making plans?
没有  只是...随便聊聊  假设的
No, just...in broad, hypothetical terms.
不不不  唐娜  听我说
N-no, no, no, Donna! Listen to me!
这一行的关键就是我们的人脉
This industry is all about who we know,
如果我们离开了  就什么都没了
and if we leave, we'll miss it.
那不叫帮助  那叫...
Okay. That's not help. Okay. That's --
那叫缓慢地扼杀我们
That's offering to kill us slowly.
-那是死刑  -不  他们只是...
- That's a death sentence. - No, they just --
他们只是觉得我们现在过得很困难
They're seeing that we're struggling is all.
我会更努力的  我会帮忙的
Well, I'll do more, okay? I-I-I'll help!
是吗
Oh, yeah?
每次宝宝哭  你就把她交给我
Every time the baby cries, you hand her back to me.
好吧  我不再那么做了
Okay. Well, I won't do that.
不仅仅是那样
Well, it's not just that.
我担心她
It's -- I'm concerned about everything
见到吃到碰到的一切
that she sees and eats and touches.
你还在她脑袋边放烟花
And you -- you're exploding fireworks next to her head.
天啊
Oh, my God.
唐娜  不就是那一个破火箭瓶吗
Donna, it was one ‭goddamn bottle rocket, okay?
如果你想走
Look, if you want to leave,
那咱们现在就收拾东西
let's just pack everything up right now.
不  我说真的
No, I'm serious!
咱们马上打包行李
Let's pack everything up right now,
搬回德州  然后我找个工作
and we'll move back to Texas, and I'll go get a job
给你爸的哪个哥们打工
working for one of your dad's friends,
这样你就能天天陪你妈打高尔夫
and you can go play golf with your mom every day.
你以为这就是我想要的吗
That's what you think I want?
我不知道你想要什么
I don't know what the hell you want.
昨天  还是我
Okay, yesterday it was -- it was me
在旧金山  闯出一番事业来
and -- and San Francisco and building something,
然后今天  我真是搞不懂
and today, I -- I don't have a clue!
你太过分了
You are being so mean right now.
我只希望我们能先停下来好好想想
I would just like us to stop and think
然后再着手去做什么事
about one thing we do before we do it.
你怀了孕  我们就结了婚
I mean, we got -- we got pregnant and then married,
然后日子就成了这样
and then we got this whole life...
而我们过成这样  我完全没有发言权
and I feel like I haven't made any of the decisions to get us here.
你还觉得你没有发言权
Oh, you feel like you didn't make any decisions?
是我单膝跪地向你求的婚吗
Was I the one who got down on one knee and proposed to you?
天啊
Oh, God.
看来还得我去照顾她
I guess I'll go get her, then.
不用  让她哭去吧
No, just let her cry!
妈妈来了  没事了
Mommy's here. It's okay.
我知道
I know.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
没事的
It's okay.
宝宝乖
baby.
没事了
It's okay.
你想要小象吗
You want your little elephant? Huh?
好了  没事的
Yeah. It's not so bad.
没关系的
It's not so bad.
没事了
Okay.
我不明白急个什么劲
I don't understand what the rush is.
我急是因为我想趁早把事情办了
The rush is I want to get this over with.
我可不想三天两头地往这儿跑
I don't want to be making a million trips back here.
所以有什么想要的  今天就拿走
So, whatever you want, you should get today.
等等
Hold on.
大件的家具  我们搬不动的
So, for big stuff, furniture we can't move ourselves,
贴绿点就留下  红点就捐了
green means keep, red means donate.
-明白吗  绿的留  红的扔  -明白
- Okay? Green, yes, red, no. - Okay. Got it.
从你们自己的房间开始吧
Start in your rooms.
别忘了你们的作业  课本
Don't forget all your schoolwork, textbooks.
孩子们
Hey, guys?
我爱你们
I love you.
也爱你
Love you, too.
我爱你
I love you.
好吧
Okay.
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
孩子们还好吗
How are the girls doing?
问得真傻  大家当然都不好
That's a stupid question. We're all doing terrible.
大家都很伤心
Everyone's terrible.
你还好吗
How are you doing?
也就那样
You know.
多谢你们来帮忙
thanks for helping out. It's...
没事的
Of course.
葬礼  真的很感人
‭The service...was beautiful.
是啊
Yeah.
你的悼词也很感人
I thought what you said was really nice.
你有留备份吗
Do you have a copy of that?
我想给孩子们留着
I'd love to save it for the girls.
我有
I do.
谢谢
Thanks.
我想说葬礼真的太感人了
I wanted to say how beautiful the service was.
真的很受触动
Like, really personal.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么
So, what,
我们从哪开始
where would you like us to start?
这个还真是
Yeah, God, it's, uh...
有点说不清楚
kind of hard to figure out.
要不你来打包戈登的衣柜吧
Maybe you could tackle Gordon's closet?
就是把衣服装进垃圾袋里准备捐给好心二手店
Just, you know, throw his clothes in garbage bags for Goodwill.
好吧
Yes.
那我从厨房着手吧
I'm gonna start in the kitchen.
如果你能把这里的东西都打包起来
If you wanted to pack up everything in here,
那就太好了
that'd be great.
好的
Yeah.
这些画还是都给孩子们留下吧
I'd just, you know, keep all the pictures for the girls, I think.
她们将来会想要的
They'll probably want them eventually.
当然  好的
Of course. Yeah, right.
你能放首歌吗
Could you put something on?
什么
What?
就是太安静了  随便放首就行
Oh, it's too quiet. Just something, anything?
好
Yeah, uh...yeah.
抱歉  就是觉得没合适的
I don't know. Sorry. Nothing feels right.
这个就很好
This is perfect.
BGM: So Far Away  By  Dire Straits
来看看
Check this out.
他可喜欢这张了
He loved this one.
这是我们在加兰市的南瓜地里拍的
This is from when we went to that pumpkin patch in Garland.
你能相信有那么一段时间
Can you believe there was a time
你对南瓜是那么着迷吗
that you got this excited about pumpkins?
我还是很喜欢南瓜啊
I still get excited about pumpkins.
南瓜最让我开心了
Pumpkins blow my mind.
其实你什么都不用扔的
You know, you don't have to get rid of anything.
你可以打包整个房间
You could just... pack up your whole room.
不  我只是不知道从哪里开始
No, it's just, I don't know where to start.
你需要帮忙吗
You need some help?
嗯
Yeah.
那我们从衣服开始  比较简单
Let's start with your clothes. That's easy.
好
Okay.
天呐
Oh, man.
所有都打包吗
So, just everything?
好吧
Yeah. I think so.
这是什么
What's this?
南加州大学
USC?
西北大学
Northwestern?
这些是什么  是备份件吗
What are these? Are these duplicates?
你递交了大学申请吧
You did send in your applications?
我现在不想谈这个  行吗
I don't want to talk about this right now, okay?
我们现在就谈
We are talking about this.
我们现在就得谈
We're talking about this right now.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
别管我
Leave me alone.
你告诉我们你递交了申请
You told us that you sent these.
怎么了
What's going on?
我没有
Well, I didn't.
我们可以私下里谈吗
Can we talk about this privately? Please?
为什么  怎么了
Why? Why?
为什么不在这里  为什么不让他们看到
Why not here? Huh? Why don't you let them see?
怎么  你害怕他们会怎么想吗
Why? Are you afraid of what they might think?
够了  我们出去
That's enough. Let's go outside.
不  让他们看看我们是多么乱套
No! Let them see what a mess we've been!
我们真的很乱套
And we have been.
我不知道你为什么这样做
I don't know why you're doing this.
你爸爸会很难过的
Your father would be -- he'd be devastated.
那幸好他现在不在  不会看到了
Well, it's a good thing that he's not here to see it, then.
这
That's...
你怎么能说出这种话
That is...that's a horrible thing to say.
你等了多长时间才拿爸爸来压我
How long did it take you to use Dad against me?
十天吗
Like 10 days?
我很惊讶你能坚持那么久
I'm surprised that you could hold out that long.
你
You are...
有时候  我都不认识你了
Sometimes I don't even know who you are anymore.
我们都受了伤  都很难受
We're all hurting. We're all upset.
你知道什么
What do you know?
你都不能忍受他
You couldn't even stand him.
乔运走了第一批东西
Joe took the first load.
你闻到了没
Do you smell that?
香烟味
Cigarette smoke.
我要宰了她
I'm gonna kill her.
她就是想激怒你
She wants to piss you off.
我17岁时也会这么干
Okay? It's the exact same thing I would've done when I was 17.
我十几岁的时候也够逆反了  但这...
I did my fair share of teenage bullshit, but this is --
她故意这么混蛋的  你就让她混蛋
She wants to be a jerk. Just let her be a jerk.
我不知道这个词足不足以形容
I don't know that ‭that's a strong enough word
她现在这副样子
for what she's being.
她居然朝我发火
I mean, she lost it at me.
明明是她没有递交申请
She's the one who didn't send them in.
是啊
Yeah.
我觉得这种情况下讲道理未必能
I don't know if reason's gonna be that helpful to you
帮到你  或是她
in this situation... or her.
或许我不该提起戈登的
Probably shouldn't have brought up Gordon.
或许吧
Probably not.
难道不是她显然不尊重我...
I mean, was it not clear that she disrespected me or --
能让我跟她谈谈吗
Could I talk to her?
可以
Yeah.
告诉她她很混蛋
Tell her she's being an asshole.
不要开门
Do not open the door.
干得漂亮
Really good one.
你妈现在完全气疯了
Your mom's totally freaking out right now.
是啊
Yeah.
虽然不是很巧妙
You don't get a million points for subtlety,
但是  确实非常有效
but still, it's very effective.
我没打算干什么  我只是需要抽支烟
I wasn't trying to do anything. I just needed a smoke.
你怎么样了
What's up?
有人吗
Hello?
在这儿
In here.
人都去哪了
Where is everyone?
远远地分散在房子的各个角落里
Scattered to the far corners of the house,
躲着我  或是躲着我
some avoiding me, others also avoiding me.
我是闻到烟味儿了吗
Do I smell cigarettes smoke?
是的
You do.
是琼妮
Joanie?
你感觉怎么样
How are you holding up?
搞什么
What the hell?
宝贝  怎么了
Sweetie, what's wrong?
爸爸的衣服在哪
Dad's clothes, where are they?
我刚从好心二手店回来
Oh, I just got back from Goodwill.
宝贝  怎么了  告诉我
Honey, what's wrong? Talk to me.
爸爸的毛衣  我本想自己留着的  但...
Dad's s-sweater, I wanted to keep it, but...
绿色的那件  没关系
It's the green one. It doesn't matter.
我...算了
I'll... Forget it.
不  不  我刚从那儿回来
No, no. I just got back.
你想要你爸的毛衣
You want your dad's sweater?
我们去拿回来
We're gonna go get it.
来啊
Come on.
我敢说比起我不上大学这件事
I bet she's more upset about the fact
她更不爽的是要告诉她的朋友们
that she has to tell her friends I'm not going to college
我不打算去上大学了
than the fact that I'm not going.
琼妮  别这样  你知道不是这样的
Joanie, come on. You know that's not true.
她就只在乎体面
Everything's appearances with her.
"看我完美的房子  完美的泳池
"Look at my perfect house and my perfect pool
还有我两个完美的女儿"
and my perfect daughters."
你知道她还熨她的牛仔裤吗
Did you know she irons her jeans?
好吧
Okay.
别说你无法收回的话
Don't say things you can't take back.
你得饶过她这一回
I need you to give her a break.
饶过她吗
Give her a break?
是的  知道为什么吗
Yeah. You know why?
你很难搞懂  因为你是个混蛋
You're hard to navigate because you're a dick.
我可以这么说  因为我也是个混蛋
And I say that because I'm a dick.
我是个大混蛋
I'm, like, huge.
混蛋之王
I'm Queen Big Dick. Like...
好吧  这么说很怪  但是
That sounded weird, but...
-是啊  -重点是  你俩
- Yeah. - ...the point is, you two...
尽量去理解你妈妈的立场
Just try and understand where your mom's coming from.
当然  反过来也是
And vice versa, of course!
但是  我像你这么大时
But, look, when I was your age,
也把我妈妈赶出了我的生活
I cut my mom out of my life, and...
你不想那么做的
you don't want to do that.
我当时有充分理由的
I mean, I had a good reason to.
我妈妈状况很糟
My mom was a mess.
她错过了我的毕业典礼
Like, missed my graduation
因为她喝了太多漱口水  就那么糟
'cause she drank too much mouthwash kind of a mess.
但还是
But still...
这些时光你要不回来的
It's time you can't get back.
我可以跟你住
I could stay with you.
我们俩住我的铁罐子吗
The two of us in my tin can?
是啊  我可以再买个拖车  开去那里
Yeah. I could get another trailer and take it out there.
那多赞
It'd be awesome.
琼妮
Joanie...
我连株植物都照顾不好
I mean, I can't even take care of a plant.
我不需要人照顾的
I don't need to be taken care of.
天呐
God.
大家都觉得我什么都做不好
Everyone looks at me like I can't do anything for myself,
-当我是小婴儿  -好吧  对不起
- like I'm in diapers. - Okay. I'm sorry.
我不是那个意思的
That -- That's really not what I meant.
我就是说
I just mean...
这就是为什么大学很棒
This is why college is so great.
你可以去那里  第一次独立生活
You get to go and be by yourself for the first time,
你可以做任何你想做的事
you can do whatever you want to do,
抽什么都行
smoke whatever you want to smoke,
学习让你感兴趣的东西
learn about the things that interest you,
如果你还不知道你对什么感兴趣
and if you don't know what those are,
也能去搞个明白
you -- you get to figure it out.
这是完美的...
I mean, it's the perfect --
我知道
I know.
你想听点什么吗
You want to put something on?
什么
What?
你不非得自己听自己的
You don't have to listen to your thing.
可以用立体声听
You can play it on the stereo.
不  你不会喜欢的
No. You wouldn't like it.
我没那么老啦
I'm not that old.
放吧
Put it on.
谈得怎么样
How'd it go?
挺好  她挺好的
Good. She's coolly awesome.
还拿走了这个
Managed to swipe these.
这是戈登奶奶的
These are Gordon's grandmother's.
打算留给姑娘们的
Gonna save them for the girls.
天呐  我总那么说
Christ, I keep saying that.
我都不知道她们会不会在意这些东西
I don't even know if they'll care about any of this stuff.
她们会的
They will.
也或者  她们会把它装进盒子里
Yeah, or they'll just... put them in a box,
放进阁楼里  等她们死后
put the box in the attic, and then, when they die,
她们的孩子会把东西拿出来说
their kids will pull it out and say,
"把这个留给孩子们好了"
"I guess we should save this for our kids."
是啊  这么说来
Yeah, that's, uh...
好黑暗
pretty dark.
我通关了游戏
I finished the game.
什么游戏
What game?
你的游戏《朝圣者》
Your game, "Pilgrim."
你真通关了
You "finished it" finished it?
是啊  可算  你做得够难的
Yeah, finally. You made it hard enough.
是啊  我是为你这样的人做的
Yeah, I made it for people like you.
很不幸  你这样的人不多了
Unfortunately, there aren't many people like you anymore.
我喜欢结尾
Well, I liked the way it ended.
朝圣者是个孩子
The pilgrim was a kid.
是啊  朝圣者是个孩子
Yeah, the pilgrim was a kid.
谢谢你玩
Thank you for playing it.
对我意义重大
Yeah, it means a lot.
在医院  博斯那事
At the hospital, with Bos,
我当时的话  不是真心的
what I said, I-I-I didn't mean it.
唐娜  没事  我都不记得你说了什么
Please, Donna, I don't even remember what you said.
嗯
Uh, yeah.
我就是说
I just mean that I, you know...
我当时迷迷瞪瞪的
me, I've been in such a fog.
我都记不得自己的名字了  更别提...
I can't even remember my own name, let alo--
嗯  我也是
Yeah, no. Me too.
我去再拿个盒子来
I'm gonna, uh, go get another box.
我们走吧
Let's just go.
不是
No.
这个  是这件吗
Oh, here. Is this it?
不是
No.
你们不能这么干  怎么...
You can't be doing that. What...
不是
No.
我们一小时前才送来的
We just dropped these off an hour ago.
我们错放了一件进来
We, uh, put something in here by mistake.
你送来的就是我们的东西了
Well, once you drop it off, it's our property.
我无法核实哪个是谁的
You know, I have no way of verifying what's what or...
-这些是T恤衫  -之类的
- These are just T-shirts. - ...or who's whatever and so on.
走吧
Let's go.
好吧  这些衣服是我一个朋友的
Okay. These clothes belonged to a friend of mine,
他已经离世了
and he's no longer with us.
我们只想找一件衣服
There's exactly one item of clothing that we're looking for.
我们送来了九个袋子
We dropped off nine bags.
这里只有八个袋子
There's only eight here.
那件毛衣就在第九个袋子里  我们必须找到它
That sweater's in the ninth bag, and we just have to find it.
这里的东西都曾经是谁的
Yeah, I mean, all this stuff belonged to somebody, man.
那个
There it is.
那是我们的包
That's our bag right there.
你怎么能知道  你无法确定
How could you know that? You can't know that.
看那个包  再看看这几个
Look at that bag! Now look at these bags.
好吧  都是垃圾袋
Okay. They look like trash bags, man.
我不知道该说什么好
I-I-I don't know what to tell you.
-对不起  -那是我们的包
- I'm sorry. - That's our bag!
这是公司政策  哥们
It's just, this is company policy, man.
我也没办法
I don't know what to say.
我们走吧
Let's go.
规矩就这样
It is what it is, man.
你有学习驾照吧
You've got your learner's permit, right?
嗯
Yeah.
把车开过来  别熄火
Pull the truck up. Keep it running.
好
Okay.
你还好吗
How you doing?
很好
Super.
你要出远门吗
Are you going somewhere?
我要搬走了
I'm moving.
我在西雅图有几个朋友
Got some friends in Seattle.
我要去试试  据说很棒的
I'm gonna give that a try. They say it's great.
嗯  听说那里很不错的
Yeah, yeah, I heard it's, um...A whole scene.
是啊
Yeah.
我不知道你要走了
I didn't know you were going.
我几天前跟乔和大家说了
I told Joe and everybody a couple days ago.
我...是临时决定的
I, uh... Sort of a quick decision.
很抱歉  我
I -- I'm sorry that I --
不能为了乔留下  但是
I couldn't stick it out there, for Joe's sake, but, um...
彗星实在有太多戈登的痕迹
There's just too much of Gordon there at Comet,
这里到处都是戈登的痕迹
and there's too much of Gordon everywhere here.
嗯
Yeah.
听上去还不赖的
Hey, you know, doesn't, uh, sound that bad.
一车的东西  重新开始
Car full of stuff, a clean slate...
大概吧
I suppose.
我之前换过好几次地方
I've pinballed around a bunch.
加入彗星时
When I landed at Comet,
我以为那种日子过去了
I thought that maybe I was done with all that, but...
或许能在西雅图待下来
perhaps Seattle will stick.
你知道它会怎么样吗
Do you know what's gonna happen with it?
彗星啊
Oh, Comet. Uh...
乔应该会继续下去
I -- I think Joe will, you know, carry it on.
应该吧
I guess.
希望是这样
I hope so.
他真的很喜欢那里
He really loves it.
他失去了这么多
With everything he's lost,
再失去它就太遗憾了
it'd be a shame if that went, too.
是啊
Yeah.
我要进去了
I'm gonna go inside.
快走  快走
Go, go! Let's go!
干什么啊  哥们
Come on, man!
快走  快走
Go, go! Go, go, go!
我去啊
Holy shit.
我可能  拿错包了
Possible that I -- I got the wrong bag.
我们可不能回去了
Well, I -- I don't think we can go back.
我觉得你可能会想拿走这个
I, uh...thought you might want to have this, so, uh...
是啊  我们很开心的
Uh, yeah, we had a lot of fun.
戈登什么都愿做
Gordon was up for anything.
这你当然最清楚了
I mean, I don't have to tell you.
是啊
Yeah.
他对你  很疯狂
Well, he was just... crazy about you.
葬礼办得很感人
It was a beautiful service, by the way.
是啊  我也觉得是
Yeah. Yeah, I thought so, too.
如果这里有什么
Hey, uh, if there's anything here
你想拿走的
that you'd like to have,
你...别客气
you should, you know, please feel free.
谢谢
Oh, uh, thanks.
我并不喜欢他的装修风格
I don't...really like his decorating style.
我从没跟他说过
I never told him that.
你上辈子是牧童咋的
It's, like, were you a vaquero in a past life or something?
是啊  他好像
Yeah, I think, uh --
是找了个装修设计师
I think he had a decorator do it --
那人偏爱纳瓦霍毯子
a decorator with a fetish for Navajo blankets.
你知道我喜欢哪张照片吗
You know what picture I love?
有张你俩的特别好的照片
There's this great one of the two of you.
你们很年轻  我也不知道是多大
You're young, and I don't know how old,
但你们都拿着啤酒
but you're both holding beers and...
戈登的鬓角很狂野
Gordon's got these wild sideburns.
我知道那张
Yeah, yeah, I know it.
你俩看上去都一副...
You both look like -- oh, man -- like -- like,
"世界  小心了"的样子
"Look out, world."
我们在一起后  我就有种
As soon as we got together, I got very, you know,
"他是我的  我希望他只属于我
"That's mine. I want him all to myself.
我想要全部的戈登"的感觉
I want all the Gordon there is."
但你已经拥有了很多的他
But you already had so much of him...
你拥有  胆大包天的鬓角戈登
You had... Hell-raising sideburns Gordon
天知道还有什么
and who knows what else.
这让我嫉妒
And it made me jealous.
好吧
Well...
我也不知道我在说什么
I don't -- I don't know what I'm saying.
该死的  戈登  怎么回事啊
Goddamn, Gordon, what the hell?
我就不打扰你了
Well, I'm gonna... get out of your hair.
谢谢
Thank you.
琼妮在她房间  你想去打个招呼吗
Joanie's, uh, up in her room if you wanted to say hi.
但是  最好小心点
But I would, um... proceed with caution.
谢谢  我会小心的
Thanks. I'll be careful.
乔去了好一会儿了
Joe's been gone for a while, huh?
是啊  或许他们停车去吃饭了
Yeah, maybe they stopped to get something to eat.
这是好事  海莉该离开这儿一会儿
That's good. Haley needs to get out of here for a little while.
乔跟她处得真好
Joe's been so great with her.
你想要这个奇怪的神父雕像吗
Hey, uh, did you want the weird priest statues or...?
我家里已经有好多了
You know, I already have so many of them at home.
我总是忘记乔跟姑娘们处得多好
I always forget how good Joe is with the girls.
特别会逗她们开心
Just really lights them right up.
因为我们是一个团队
Because we're a team.
抱歉
Sorry.
你没事吧
You okay?
我就是在这里发现他的  我走了
This is where I found him. I'm gonna go.
谁啊
Hello?
进来
Come in.
博斯来了  他带了食物来
Bos just showed up. He brought food.
妈妈要我来看看你需不需要帮助
Mom wanted me to see if you needed any help.
我并不想要这些东西
I don't really want any of this stuff.
只想拿我的CD和照片
Just my CDs and my pictures.
怎么了
What?
你为什么不申请大学
Why didn't you apply to college?
我反正也进不去
Well, I wasn't gonna get into any of them.
你打算干什么
What are you gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我会想清楚的
I'll figure it out.
捐了你
Donating you.
你试试看
Like to see you try.
至少他们还有你
At least they have you.
完全跟他们期待的一样
Exactly what they want in every way.
也不是完全一样
Well, not every way.
过来
Come here.
傻瓜
Dummy.
你不会也离开吧
You're not gonna go away, too, are you?
乔  你尝过我的辣椒酱吗
Joe, you ever have my chili?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
这是博斯沃思的家族菜谱  代代相传的
It's an old Bosworth family recipe, handed down.
秘密在于肉桂  真的
The secret's in the cinnamon. Yeah.
你要把肉桂
See, what you do is, you take that cinnamon,
放在橱柜里
and you put it in the cupboard
远离你的辣椒
and keep it away from your chili
因为它根本就不该出现在辣椒酱里
'cause it got no damn business being there in the first place.
我记得
You know, I remember...
我以前都没注意过戈登
I didn't really even notice Gordon
直到他开始跟你们做"巨人"电脑
until he started working on "the Giant" with y'all.
我以前喊他汤渍
I used to call him Soup Stain...
-因为他总是...  -我不能...
- ...'cause he always had a - I'm not...
我现在还做不到
ready to do that.
帮我个忙  尝一下
You do me a favor and taste this real quick?
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
我不管你饿不饿
I don't care if you're hungry.
我只想确保姑娘们不会嫌太辣
Just want to make sure it's not too hot for the girls.
她们一周都没好好吃
They been eating crap all week.
我想确保她们吃顿好的
I want to make sure they get a good meal.
尝尝看辣度怎么样就行
Just check the damn spice level on that, if you could.
我想确保大家都会吃
I want to make sure everyone's gonna eat it.
挺好的
It's good.
不太辣吗
Not too spicy?
不
No.
真的很棒
It's really good.
那就好
Good.
饭待会儿就好
The food will be ready in a minute
把大家叫齐吧
if you want to gather the troops.
好的
Yeah, sure.
你知道卡梅伦去哪了吗
Uh, do you know where Cameron is?
不知道
No.
我就...
Hey, I just...
需要点时间
needed a -- a minute.
嗯
Yeah.
博斯带了食物来  我们待会儿要吃饭了
Bos brought some food, so we're gonna eat soon,
要一起来吗
if you want to join.
天呐
Oh, God.
这太难承受了
This is too much.
我不知道...
I didn't know...
来这儿会这么难
it would be this hard to be here.
没事的  我不...
It's okay. I didn't, um...
我不是想弄得以我为中心的
I don't mean to make this about me.
没事  以你为中心吧
Please, make it about you.
我觉得大家都在哄我
I feel like everybody's been handling me.
没人知道该怎么做
Nobody knows how to act.
我很喜欢大家说"你还好吗"
Well, I really love it when people say, "How are you doing?"
我确定我就问过你这个
I'm pretty sure I asked you that.
当然了
Yeah, of course you did.
不然你还能说什么
'Cause what else are you gonna say?
然后  要怎么回答呢
And then, yeah, how do you answer?
撑着呢
Hangin' in there.
没错
That's right.
因为诚实回答的话
'Cause to answer honestly,
你就得喋喋不休地说好几天
you'd have to talk incessantly for days,
谁想听呢  是吧
and who wants to listen to that, right?
那么
So...
你还好吗
How are you doing?
撑着呢
Hangin' in there.
我失去了一个好...朋友
I lost a really good...friend.
我本来就没有多少好朋友
And I don't have that many of those to spare.
我知道  我真可怜
I know, like...poor me.
但我一直不太会
But I've always had a bit of trouble
发展那样的关系
making those sorts of connections.
我生命中没有多少人
There's just not a lot of people in my life.
我也是
Me neither.
我都没法跟乔说话
I can't even talk to Joe.
为什么
Why not?
我们现在  心境不同
We're at...different places in our life.
这让他想起了很多事
This has brought up a lot of stuff for him.
比如呢
Like what?
他想要孩子
He wants kids.
我...
I-I'm...
如果你想要  我觉得你会是个好...
If you want that, I think you'd be great --
不  我不想要
No, I...do not.
我从来没想要过
I mean, I just never have.
我也不觉得这点会变
And I don't see that changing.
那就别了
Well, then don't.
真的很难的
It's really hard, and I...
你必须真的很想要才能做到差不多好
You have to really want it to do a halfway decent job.
而且
I mean...
即便如此
Even then...
你一直想要的
You always wanted it.
这个嘛
I mean, I...
我并没打算刚出学校就怀上
I didn't plan on getting pregnant right out of school,
但是  对  我一直想要的
yeah, yeah, I-I always wanted it.
没有那种感觉也没什么不对
And there's nothing wrong with not feeling that way.
谢谢
Thank you.
但如果你改主意了
If you change your mind, though,
我有个17岁的娃  我正想打发走
I've got a 17-year-old I'm looking to unload, so...
好吧
Whatever.
我想他
I -- I miss him.
我也是
So do I.
我也想你
And I miss you, too.
我在呢
I'm here.
我花了...
I spent so much...
我花了那么多时间跟他说
I spent so much time telling him...
他都做错了什么
everything he did wrong...
他是做错了很多事
He did a ton wrong.
好香啊
Something smells good.
当然  这是祖传菜谱
Sure. It's an old family recipe.
如果谁想要酸豆配辣椒酱
Oh, well, if anybody wants capers in their chili,
冰箱里有14罐呢
there's about 14 jars of it in the fridge.
你好大胆
How dare you.
我父亲会从坟里跳出来的
My father'd leap out of his grave.
谢谢
Thank you.
那天看到一份菜谱  往辣椒酱里加菠萝
Saw a recipe the other day called for pineapple in chili.
什么啊
What?
能相信吗  菠萝
Can you believe that? Pineapple? In the --
这国家是怎么了
What the hell is this country coming to?
-不了  谢谢  -那
- Oh, no, thank you. - So, um...
接下来怎么办  谁来取这些东西
what, uh, happens next? Who comes for all this stuff?
有家公司会负责
Uh, there's a company that takes care
家具和物品的拍卖
of the sale of the furniture and things.
什么那么好笑
What's so funny?
私人笑话  你不会懂的
It's an inside joke. You wouldn't get it.
海莉
Haley?
抱歉我没拿回你爸的毛衣
I'm sorry I couldn't get your dad's sweater back.
没事的
That's okay.
你记得爸爸曾想让我们相信
Do you remember when Dad tried to convince us
他赢过一个卡拉马祖的吃热狗大赛吗
that he won a hot-dog eating contest in Kalamazoo?
那不是真的吗
That wasn't true?
亲爱的  不是哦
Oh, honey, no.
他干吗要编那样的谎话
Why would he make that up?
我不知道
I don't know.
他大概觉得挺逗的吧
I -- I think he thought it was funny.
-逗死了  -爸爸好怪
- That's hilarious. - Dad was such a weirdo.
乔  能把盐递给我吗
Hey, Joe, can you pass the salt?
好
Yeah.
你房间怎么样了  亲爱的
How's your room looking, sweetheart?
乱成一团
Uh, it's a mess.
天啊  不  妈妈  老天爷啊
Oh, God, no, Mom, for God's sake,
别飞回来
do not fly back here for this.
他很快就会回来的
It's... He'll be back soon.
不  妈妈...
No, Mo--
天啊  我就不该告诉你
God, I should never have told you.
不是大事的
It's not a big deal.
我觉得他就是压力太大  好吗
I think he's just under a lot of stress, okay?
就是...
It's...
他很快会回来的
He'll be back soon.
我知道  他很快就会回来的
Oh, I know, I know. He'll be back soon.
他会的  我知道
He will. I know.
*我的好宝贝  擦干眼泪*
*Baby mine, dry your eyes*
*把头枕在我心上*
*Rest your head close to my heart*
*永不分离*
*Never to part*
*我的好宝贝*
*Baby of mine*
再不许那么对我了
Don't you ever do that to me again, okay?
我不会了
I won't.